Hello guys, in the thumbel, you saw that I have
forbidden people from going to India's number one cancer
hospital, Tata Memorial Hospital, Mumbai.
Why? Let's discuss in this video
which patient should
go to Tata Hospital and which patient should
not go to Tata Hospital.
We all go to
Tata Hospital with great hope. I also went to Tata Hospital with my
father with the hope of getting him completely cured and bringing him back,
but that did not happen.
He passed away on August 27th. I am
making this video so that you do not make the same mistake that I did. Let's
come directly to the main point,
why you should not go to Tana Hospital.
If you or your patient
needs surgery for cancer treatment, then I would
advise you not to go to Tata Hospital. You can get the
surgery done in any private hospital
if your financial condition is
good.
Now you will ask why you should not go.
Point number one, the doctors of Tata Hospital do
not take any risk. If you or
your patient has BP, sugar or any other
disease which can be risky in surgery,
then they will not do the surgery, they will
not do it until the condition becomes normal.  The
reason for this is that he will send you to his
doctor and that doctor will keep
checking you every 10 days until your
sugar and blood pressure become suitable for surgery.
This takes a lot of time. It can take a month and a half.
So this is the first point.
Point number two, we all know that this is the
number one cancer hospital in India and
it is very crowded, so much so that if
you go for a basic MRI CT scan,
you may have an appointment for two weeks or 20 days. That
means you have a 20-day appointment today.
After 20 days, you will have an MRI
CT scan, which also takes a lot of time.
And the CT scan has to be
done again after a month and a half because the
old one does not work. So, again you will have to
give 20 days and get an appointment for the
CT scan, which takes a lot of time.
Point number three, if your cancer is
not confirmed, then I would say that you should
not
come here because to get a BiP C, you have to wait
in a long line for seven days
because their seven days are full.
You will get the test for the test only after six days.
If you have tested positive today, you will get an appointment
for the test after six days. Then the result will
come after a day. So it takes 17-18 days,
which is a lot of days. And if it is not
found then it will be repeated again. Because of this also a
lot of time is wasted. There is a lot of crowd,
that is why everyone has to give this time. So for
this reason I would say that you should not go
if your cancer is not confirmed and the
doctors here get so engrossed in finding the cancer that they do
not pay attention to the rest of the patient's health. Then
one day you will be told that the disease has progressed a lot and
now nothing can be done. You will be
asked to go home with funnel.
Something similar happened to me. My
father had cancer in the pancreas. The first time
we did the test outside Tata Hospital, it did
not come in there. So we went to the hospital. After
looking at all the reports, they said that they will do
direct surgery. We spent three months doing the surgery.
Then after three months, they said that surgery cannot be done because the
cancer has progressed. So they said that
chemotherapy should be given.  Then we were
sent to a chemotherapy doctor, we went there and had to get
BiPs done twice, it did
not come the first time, then it came the second time, then doing this
two months passed, three months there,
two months here, then they said that the
disease has progressed a lot, now nothing can be done
and I was asked to go home, so
this is it, in which situation you should
not go to Tata Hospital, now comes
in which situation you should go to Tata Hospital,
point number one, if you have to
take chemotherapy then you should definitely go to Tata Hospital,
chemotherapy is given very well in Tata Hospital,
yes it is a little longer
but if your cancer is confirmed and
all the reports are good then if you go then
your chemo starts within a week
which is a very good
thing, so if your
hemoglobin is above 9 and it is
important for you and your chemo, it is important for you to stay healthy
because otherwise you will not have the capacity to bear the chemo, so
you should have the capacity to bear the chemo, so if you are a little better
and your cancer is confirmed then you can go for
chemo
Point number two, if your
financial condition is very bad, then you
can go to Tata Hospital. In any situation, if
you need chemo or surgery,
you can go to the hospital because the
facilities available at Tata Hospital are
not available in any private hospital.
And it is not that this happened in my condition, this happened
in everyone's condition. Many people have recovered and
come back, so you can go
if you do not have any money at all.
Point number three, if your patient is a
child, then you can go to Tata Hospital
because the child is treated with more care there
and is fully
supported financially. In general, you will
not have to spend any money on hospital
expenses, so you can go without any cost. If the child is older,
they pay a little less attention. For example, if the child is
above 55, then the
attention is paid a little less, so the child does
not face any problem. So this was some of my
experience with Tata Memorial.
If you have any questions, you
can ask in the comments. And if you like it, then
Like, see you
in the next video